<idea-plugin>
    <id>com.hotpath.heatmap</id>
    <name>Hot Path Heatmap</name>
    <vendor email="pelyhearon@gmail.com" url="https://github.com/neoralphy">neoralphy</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
        <p><b>Static hot path heatmap for PHP and JavaScript/TypeScript.</b></p>
        <p><b>Why?</b> In source, every call reads as equally cheap: <code>$user-&gt;getId()</code>
        looks exactly like <code>$user-&gt;calculateTheMeaningOfLife()</code> — yet one is a trivial
        field access and the other may fan out through services, loops, and a repository. Hot Path
        Heatmap was built to make that difference <i>visible at a glance</i>, so you notice the
        expensive call before it becomes a production problem.</p>
        <p>It highlights method call sites that may trigger expensive downstream execution paths
        — deep call chains, nested loops, repository / HTTP-client access, high fan-out — by
        statically composing cached method summaries from the IDE's PSI and indexes.</p>
        <p>Each flagged call gets a severity-colored outline, a cost score in the gutter, and a
        tooltip explaining <i>why</i>. This is a static estimate, not a runtime profiler — it
        exists to give an early visual warning: <i>"this innocent-looking line may be expensive."</i></p>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <b>0.1.16</b>
        <ul>
          <li>Added a <b>Sensitivity</b> setting (Low / Medium / High) that controls how expensive a
              call site must be before it's flagged. Higher presets raise every band cutoff so
              fewer, only-costlier call sites light up. The previous thresholds are now the "Low"
              preset; the new default is <b>Medium</b>, so the heatmap is less noisy out of the box.</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.1.15</b>
        <ul>
          <li>New icon set: refreshed plugin icon and toolbar toggle (on/off) icons.</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.1.14</b>
        <ul>
          <li>Minimum IDE is now 2025.3. The toggle now uses the non-deprecated daemon-restart
              API (the old form was deprecated in 2025.3), so the plugin no longer reports a
              deprecated-API usage on 2025.3+. (If you are on 2024.2–2025.2, stay on 0.1.13.)</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.1.13</b>
        <ul>
          <li>Made the "very high" score clearly distinct from "high": "high" is now a definite
              orange and "very high" a pure red, so the top two severity bands no longer look
              alike.</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.1.12</b>
        <ul>
          <li>PHP and JavaScript are now <i>optional</i> dependencies. The plugin installs in any
              IntelliJ-based IDE (not only PhpStorm) and activates whichever of the two languages
              is present. This fixes the "binary incompatible — package com.jetbrains.php not
              found" error reported when verifying against IDEs that don't bundle PHP (e.g.
              IntelliJ IDEA, WebStorm).</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.1.11</b>
        <ul>
          <li>Added back an inline marker: a bold <i>straight</i> underline on the call name
              (distinct from the wavy underlines IDE diagnostics use), alongside the gutter
              score. It is emitted on the lowest highlighting layer, so any warning/error on the
              same token always takes precedence — the marker is suppressed there rather than
              doubling up or painting over the diagnostic.</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.1.10</b>
        <ul>
          <li>The estimate now shows only as a colored score badge in the editor gutter — the
              inline marker on the code is gone. With nothing painted on the code text, the
              gutter number can use an intuitive warm yellow → orange → red heat ramp without
              ever colliding with IDE warnings or errors.</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.1.9</b>
        <ul>
          <li>Call-site marker is now a purple background "heat tint" that deepens as the
              estimated cost rises — the literal heatmap look. It uses a single purple hue and
              no underline/box, so it never collides with IDE warnings or errors (which use
              wavy underlines and yellow/red).</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.1.8</b>
        <ul>
          <li>Call-site marker is now a full boxed outline, and the palette moved to a cool
              blue → magenta → purple ramp (no warm yellow/orange/red tones, which read as
              warnings).</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.1.7</b>
        <ul>
          <li>New call-site marker: a dotted underline instead of a solid box, so it no longer
              reads as an error. The severity ramp now tops out at purple (amber → orange →
              magenta → purple) rather than an alarming red.</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.1.6</b>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed call sites in TypeScript files being analyzed and painted twice
              (doubled gutter score and outline). TypeScript is now handled once, via
              its JavaScript base language.</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.1.5</b>
        <ul>
          <li>Added a plugin icon (shown in the Plugins list and on the Marketplace).</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.1.4</b>
        <ul>
          <li>Exclusion now follows the IDE's own directory marks instead of matching path
              strings: folders marked <b>Excluded</b> and <b>Test Sources Root</b> (via
              Mark Directory as…) are skipped by default, each toggleable in settings.
              Built-in/library code is always skipped.</li>
          <li>Aligned the toolbar flame icon with the Run/Debug controls.</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.1.3</b>
        <ul>
          <li>Added a show/hide toggle button to the main toolbar (next to Run/Debug),
              also available in the Tools and editor right-click menus. A lit flame means
              the heatmap is on; a slashed flame means it is off.</li>
          <li>While hidden, no cost scores are calculated at all.</li>
          <li>Expanded the plugin description with the motivation behind it.</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.1.2</b>
        <ul>
          <li>Removed the upper IDE-compatibility bound so the plugin installs on
              2024.2 and all future PhpStorm builds. Verified compatible against the
              2024.2 and 2025.3 (253) lines.</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.1.1</b>
        <ul>
          <li>Listing metadata: license, vendor, and description updates.</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.1.0</b>
        <ul>
          <li>Initial release.</li>
          <li>Static hot-path heatmap for PHP and JavaScript/TypeScript.</li>
          <li>Severity-colored marker, gutter cost score, and an explanatory tooltip.</li>
          <li>Configurable heuristics, traversal limits, and vendor/test exclusion.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <!--
      The PHP and JavaScript integrations are OPTIONAL dependencies. The core cost engine is
      language-neutral, so the plugin installs in any IntelliJ-based IDE and activates whichever of
      PHP / JavaScript is actually present (PhpStorm bundles both). Each optional dependency's
      config file registers that language's external annotator and its LanguageSupport adapter, so
      the language-specific code (and the PHP/JS PSI it references) is only loaded when that plugin
      is installed — which is what keeps the plugin binary-compatible with IDEs that lack PHP.
    -->
    <depends optional="true" config-file="hotpath-php.xml">com.jetbrains.php</depends>
    <depends optional="true" config-file="hotpath-js.xml">JavaScript</depends>

    <extensionPoints>
        <!-- One language adapter per supported language, contributed from the optional deps above. -->
        <extensionPoint name="languageSupport"
                        interface="com.hotpath.heatmap.analysis.LanguageSupport"
                        dynamic="true"/>
    </extensionPoints>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <projectService
            serviceImplementation="com.hotpath.heatmap.analysis.MethodSummaryService"/>

        <applicationService
            serviceImplementation="com.hotpath.heatmap.settings.HotPathSettings"/>

        <applicationConfigurable
            parentId="tools"
            instance="com.hotpath.heatmap.settings.HotPathConfigurable"
            id="com.hotpath.heatmap.settings"
            displayName="Hot Path Heatmap"/>
    </extensions>

    <actions>
        <action
            id="com.hotpath.heatmap.ToggleHeatmap"
            class="com.hotpath.heatmap.actions.ToggleHeatmapAction"
            icon="/icons/heatmap.svg"
            text="Toggle Hot Path Heatmap"
            description="Show or hide the hot path heatmap. While hidden, no cost scores are calculated.">
            <!-- Button in the main header toolbar, next to the Run/Debug controls. -->
            <add-to-group group-id="MainToolbarRight" anchor="first"/>
            <add-to-group group-id="ToolsMenu" anchor="last"/>
            <add-to-group group-id="EditorPopupMenu" anchor="last"/>
        </action>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>
